JANET YODER

7205 W. 21st. Street Greeley, CO 80634 kajcyoder@comcast.net

www.linkedin.com/in/janetyoder Cell: 970-396-9428

SUMMARY

An accomplished product/program manager and software engineer. Top strengths include: excellent interpersonal skills, utilizing teamwork to get results, and being detail-oriented without losing sight of the overall goal. Experience in:

- Software Development and Maintenance
- Product/Project/Program Management
- Scrum Master and Agile practices
- Escalation Management/ Process Creation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Microsoft Project, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Visio, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
- Visual Studio, JavaScript, ¡Query, C++, C#, COM, MFC, HTML/HTML5, CSS3, XML
- SharePoint, Subversion, GitHub, Brackets, HP Quality Center/ALM, XPlanner, VMWare, InstallShield

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALLPROWEBTOOLS, Fort Collins, CO

2014-presentt

Web Developer

Creating email ads, coupons, and other graphic design content. Have created numerous websites using Bootstrap and AllProWebTools framework. Gaining experience in HTML5, CSS3, PHP, and MySQL.

HEWLETT-PACKARD, Greeley/Fort Collins, CO

Sustained Engineering Lead for Windows Software (2013)

Led the team to create processes for managing customer issues and pre-sales opportunities for a \$182 million scanner software portfolio.

- Drove to completion prototypes and patches for current customers and "big deal" solutions for world-wide business opportunities ranging up to millions of dollars.
- Directed prioritization meetings to obtain cross-functional alignment.
- Managed off-shore developers and testers to achieve customer satisfaction and contract award goals.
- Debugged source code written in C++, COM, and MFC for root cause, verified fixes, and determined deployment strategy.

Scanner and Camera Product Engineer and Program Manager (1997-2013)

Managed the requirements, schedule and software solution life-cycle for HP 's market leading scanners and HP Photosmart cameras.

- Defined and documented the software definition and drove on-time solution delivery for Scanjet, Deskjet, Photosmart, and Officejet devices.
- Wrote requirement specifications, design documents, CD structures, and readme for Scanjets.
- Directed cross-functional meetings designed to improve the communication and linkages between software, firmware, customer satisfaction, and marketing.
- Collaborated with external partner companies on software definitions to ensure the product met the requirements and the customer needs.
- Identified and resolved issues with product plans, marketing materials and support documents to ensure the correct information is communicated to the customer.

Janet Yoder Page 2

Certified Scrum Master (2009-2012)

Led the team transition from a waterfall product life-cycle to using Agile. Managed the Scrum process to ensure the Scrum values, practices and rules were enacted and enforced.

- Instructed the Commercial Scan Software Team on Agile concepts/processes.
- Conducted sprint review and planning meetings to review the team's accomplishments and determine commitments for the next sprint, resulting in better team focus, meeting goals and improved quality.
- Facilitated daily scrums ensuring the committed stories were worked on with no blocking issues.
- Led or participated in the prioritization of the product backlog.

Software Developer (1993-2003)

Developed code and maintained components shipped with HP Scanjet Scanner solutions, HP Photosmart Digital Cameras, HP Personal and Photo Printers and HP All-in-One devices.

- Collaborated cross-divisionally on designing a COM component to allow customers to send scans directly to other software applications. Prototyped code using XML, XPATH, COM, and C++.
- Created merge modules using InstallShield's Window's Installer. Implemented install configuration files for the master software build.
- Wrote a C++ executable that communicated to a COM DLL for printing and faxing functionality.
- Prototyped in MFC, developed, tested, and fixed defects for new features in scanning software.

Developer Solutions Toolkit Management, Development and Support (1995-1997)

Worked with Developer Solutions Team to take toolkits from conception to product release.

- Directed developer solution team on life-cycle, processes, specifications, and test documentation. Owned the developer solution's vintage chart and schedule.
- Defined/implemented HP Intelligent Scanning Technology Destination Certification Program.
- Provided technical support for destination beta sites and developer escalation support.

EDUCATION

University of Northern Colorado Greeley, CO

Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics, Emphasis: Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL AND PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

Aims Community College Greeley, CO

Graphics Software and Applications Certificate

• Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign CS5 and CS6, Typography and Layout, Electronic Pre-press

Complete Web Authoring Class

• HTML5 and CSS3 – Created a 5 page website for the final project.

Front Range Community College Longmont, CO

WebLab Certificate

• HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, UI/UX Design

Corporate Sponsored Training

- 1999-2003 Java, Fundamentals of XML, Programming with C#, Power ASP .NET Programming
- 2004-2007 Project Management, Program Management, Project Leadership and Communication, TCP/IP Workshop, Managing Offshore Vendors

- 2010 2012 Agile Estimating and Planning, Coaching Agile Teams, Demonstrating Responsibility: The Mindset of an Agile Leader, Designing the Agile, Organization Who Does What, Certified Scrum Master Training, Windows CE Development, Microsoft SharePoint 2010
- 2012-2013 Writing Windows 8 Metro Applications with XAML (2012), Windows Store Data binding and MVVM